Minal Vaity

A software engineer, with 2 years of experience in Web-based applications using Agile methodology, with a good understanding of both business processes and software development and worked in three different teams in a project for a US client.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Information Technology and Management (Software Development)

May 2021

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, Illinois, USA

Current GPA (4.0/4.0)

Coursework: Object-Oriented Application Development, Rich Internet Applications, Project Management, Open Source Programming, Advanced Software Programming, Open-Source Intelligent Device Applications, Web RTC, Cloud Computing, Software testing and Maintenance.

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

June 2017

Rajiv Gandhi Institute of Technology, Mumbai, India

Coursework: Data Structures, Analysis of Algorithms, Operating Systems, Web Development Technologies, Mobile Communication and Computing, Data warehousing and Mining, Big Data Analytics

SKILLS

Programming skills: C, C++, JAVA, J2EE, Python, HTML5 (CSS3 Styling), Javascript, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Redux, JQuery **Tools:** MySQL Server, Eclipse, Visual Studio, NetBeans, Android SDK, IntelliJ, PyCharm, Excel, Microsoft Office, Putty, Powershell, selenium, Jira, Tableau, Git, AWS, Confluence, Linux OS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, CYBAGE SOFTWARE PVT. LTD., India

July 2017 - June 2019

- Analyzed the existing business application, reviewed and analyzed a few project requirements
- Enhanced existing systems to handle new web layout and 3 functionalities and configured the content in the Enterprise Desktop which led to 10% increase in sales.
- Accomplished the tasks of the development of 2 important components of the application in the Spring MVC framework
- Developed core java classes using Exceptions and Unit test cases using the Junit testing framework which improved the software product development process by 30%
- Implemented user interface using JavaScript, JSP, and JDBC leading to 40% increase in customer satisfaction ratings
- Experienced in configuration and administration using Apache Tomcat
- Updated and maintained the database on the server using SQL for keeping track of every shop request generated on UI which were almost 50,000 per hour
- Created and executed test cases using Selenium Automation tool and Cucumber which reduced the number of bugs and increase software quality
- BI/Analytics documentation and status report writing using Tableau for improved performance check.

Graduate Teaching Assistant, Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, Illinois, USA

Sept 2020 - Present

· Assisting course instructor, evaluate assignments and projects, mentor tackling the issues faced by students with their tasks.

PROJECTS

• Simple Dice Rolling Game Application

Sept 2020

Built an android game application which calculates the score of a player after rolling three dices for triples and doubles.

• Rock-Paper-Scissor Game using Python

Sept 2020

Devised an interactive game of rock-paper-scissor that can be played with the computer by a single player.

Typing Speed Test web application

June 2020 May 2020

Designed a UI to test the typing speed which calculates the 100% accurate time taken to type a particular text.

Online Course Management System

Developed a maven web-based application using payara server for course management using advance software programming tools and concepts which had 3 types of users – instructors, students and teaching assistants.

Change Calculator using Python Tkinker

May 2020

Devised a change calculator that number and type of coins and returns their value against a dollar with total.

News Gateway Android Application

May 2020

Built an android application which displays 10 current news articles from a wide variety of news sources covering a range of news categories. It is built using Android X library jetpacks, google login API and News.org API

Medical Student Study Application

Dec 2019

Introduced a study application for medical students using JSP and Apache Tomcat Server where students categorize their study material in 3 categories – muscle anatomy, drugs and diseases.

CERTIFICATIONS

• JavaScript Essential Training

• Android Development Essential Training

June 2020 May 2020

• Python Data Analysis

April 2020

ORGANIZATIONS & LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

• Machine Learning at Illinois Institute of Technology - Social Media Head

Aug 2020 - Present

• Indian Student Association, Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago IL – Events Head

Sept 2019 – May 2020

• Incubator Cell Committee, Rajiv Gandhi Institute of Technology, Mumbai – Executive member

Aug 2016 - Nov 2016